<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forecasting on Richie Lee</title>
    <link>/tags/forecasting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forecasting on Richie Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/forecasting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Econometric Panel Data Modelling: Albert Heijn (Ahold Delhaize)</title>
      <link>/post/2022_heterogeneity_ah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022_heterogeneity_ah/</guid>
      <description>TL:DR In collaboration with Albert Heijn, this study explores the dynamics between product labels and consumer buying behaviour. The study successfully addressed the challenges posed by panel data, such as unobserved heterogeneity, omitted variable bias, and seasonality, demonstrating the usefulness of the micro-econometric toolkit.
The positive reception of the findings and methodologies led to an invitation to present the results at Albert Heijn&amp;rsquo;s Data Science department&amp;rsquo;s Knowledge Exchange initiative. The main contribution of the study is the proof-of-concept and simplifiction of micro-econometric methods for these specific use-cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCA Machine Learning Hybrid Models: Real Estate Forecasting</title>
      <link>/post/2021_factor_ml_forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021_factor_ml_forecasting/</guid>
      <description>TL:DR The objective of this study is to predict Dutch House prices using macroeconomic variables that were collected from Government open-source databases. Given the high number of explanatory variables relative to the number of observations, we recognise a good fit with parsimonious modelling. These models are characterised by their great explanatory power from minimal resources and are especially valuable in cases of limited or low-frequency data.
The methods considered follow Kim &amp;amp; Swanson (2018) hybrid model design, where we combine factor modelling techniques (PCA, ICA, Sparse PCA) and machine learning ensembles (Boosting) and regularization methods (Elastic Net, Ridge regression, LASSO).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
