<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PyTorch on Richie Lee</title>
    <link>/tags/pytorch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PyTorch on Richie Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/pytorch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deep Reinforcement Learning: Game Automation</title>
      <link>/post/2021_reinforcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021_reinforcement/</guid>
      <description>TL:DR This post contains a brief introduction to deep-learning based reinforcement learning in the form of simple/standard REINFORCE, Actor-Critic (A2C) and Deep Q-learning (DQN) algorithms with a few extensions. When tackling the CartPole-v1 problem, an open-source playground example by OpenAI, we compare the models in terms of game performance, stability and compute. The code was written using Python with PyTorch.
Introduction: Reinforcement Learning (RL) Reinforcement learning (RL) is a machine learning strategy where an agent learns decision-making skills by moving from state to state by interacting with an closed environment without relying on any data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNN Sentiment Classification: Movie Reviews</title>
      <link>/post/2021_rnn_sentiment_classifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021_rnn_sentiment_classifier/</guid>
      <description>TL:DR The objective is to accurately identify whether a movie was positively or negatively received through text reviews from IMDb. This is a common NLP challenge that is known as Sentiment Classification. The proposed algorithm is a Recurrent Neural Network (RNN). Especially the ability to capture complex relations and sequential dependencies in text data is what becomes valuable here. In this brief post, a well-known RNN implementation, a LSTM, is benchmarked against other deep learning implementations and checked for robustness.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
