<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NLP on Richie Lee</title>
    <link>/tags/nlp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NLP on Richie Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/nlp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Duplicate Detection &amp; Text Analysis: Ecommerce Products</title>
      <link>/post/2021_lsh_duplicate_detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021_lsh_duplicate_detection/</guid>
      <description>TL:DR This article explore the development of a scalable product duplicate detection framework for E-commerce data. Our approach involves combining clustering (Locality-Sensitive Hashing - LSH) with classification, supported by thorough data preprocessing using text analysis and NLP techniques.
The overall approach is summarised in the following diagram: Context With the ever increasing relevance of online shopping and customers are becoming more comfortable with online platforms with user experience therefore playing a crucial role in driving sales and preventing churn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNN Sentiment Classification: Movie Reviews</title>
      <link>/post/2021_rnn_sentiment_classifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021_rnn_sentiment_classifier/</guid>
      <description>TL:DR The objective is to accurately identify whether a movie was positively or negatively received through text reviews from IMDb. This is a common NLP challenge that is known as Sentiment Classification. The proposed algorithm is a Recurrent Neural Network (RNN). Especially the ability to capture complex relations and sequential dependencies in text data is what becomes valuable here. In this brief post, a well-known RNN implementation, a LSTM, is benchmarked against other deep learning implementations and checked for robustness.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
