<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Richie Lee</title>
    <link>https://richie-lee.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Richie Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://richie-lee.github.io/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PCA Machine Learning Hybrid Models: Real Estate Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://richie-lee.github.io/post/2021_factor_ml_forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richie-lee.github.io/post/2021_factor_ml_forecasting/</guid>
      <description>TL:DR The objective of this study is to predict Dutch House prices using macroeconomic variables that were collected from Government open-source databases. Given the high number of explanatory variables relative to the number of observations, we recognise a good fit with parsimonious modelling. These models are characterised by their great explanatory power from minimal resources and are especially valuable in cases of limited or low-frequency data.
The methods considered follow Kim &amp;amp; Swanson (2018) hybrid model design, where we combine factor modelling techniques (PCA, ICA, Sparse PCA) and machine learning ensembles (Boosting) and regularization methods (Elastic Net, Ridge regression, LASSO).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Classification: Movie Reviews</title>
      <link>https://richie-lee.github.io/post/2021_rnn_sentiment_classifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richie-lee.github.io/post/2021_rnn_sentiment_classifier/</guid>
      <description>Context The objective is to accurately identify whether a movie was positively or negatively received through text reviews from IMDb. This is a process that is often referred to as Sentiment Classification. Though seemingly trivial, there were multiple aspects that made this problem more challenging:
Input data size is not consistent (different review lengths) Small differences are often relevant, ruling out standard similarity methods There are a lot of distinct dependencies across words Time constraints: 1 week for coding &amp;amp; reporting Data Amazons IMDb (Internet Movie Database) is known as the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular source for movie reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
